So let me be more specific.
再具体讲解一下
Let's look at the following four points: two blue and two red
我们来看看图中的这四个点 两个蓝点和两个红点
and two models that classify them,
以及两个对它们进行分类的模型
the one on the left and the one on the right.
也就是左侧和右侧的两个模型
Quick. Which model looks better? You are correct.
快速思考下 哪个看上去更好？没错
The model on the right is much better since it
右侧的更好
classifies the four points correctly whereas
因为它对四个点都分类正确了
the model in the left gets two points correctly and two points incorrectly.
而左侧的模型让两个点分类正确 另外两个分类错误
But let's see why the model in the right is better from the probability perspective.
我们从概率角度讨论一下为何右侧的模型更好
And by that, we'll show you that the arrangement in the right is
通过这一讨论 我们将说明与左侧相比
much more likely to happen than the one in the left.
右侧的情况更有可能发生
So let's recall that our prediction is ŷ = σ(Wx+b) and that that
我们的预测是 ŷ = σ(Wx+b)
is precisely the probability of a point being labeled positive which means blue.
即点被标为正点（蓝点）的概率
So for the points in the figure,
对于图中的点
let's say the model tells you that the probability of being blue are 0.9,
假设模型说是蓝色的概率为 0.9
0.6, 0.3, and 0.2.
0.6 0.3 和 0.2
Notice that the points in the blue region are much more likely to be
注意 蓝色区域的点是蓝点的可能性较大
blue and the points in the red region are much less likely to be blue.
而红色区域的点是蓝点的可能性较低
Now obviously, the probability of being red is one minus the probability of being blue.
很明显的是 红色的概率是 1 减去蓝色的概率
So in this case, the probability of some of the points being red are 0.1,
这里 某些点是红色的概率为 0.1
0.4, 0.7 and 0.8.
0.4 0.7 和 0.8
Now what we want to do is we want to calculate the probability of
现在我们要做的是
the four points are of the colors that they actually are.
计算四个点是实际颜色的概率
This means the probability that the two red points
也就是红点是红色
are red and that the two blue points are blue.
蓝点是蓝色的概率
Now if we assume that the colors of the points are independent events then
如果假设点的颜色是独立事件
the probability for the whole arrangement is
那么整个图表的概率是
the product of the probabilities of the four points.
四个点概率的积
This is equal to 0.1 × 0.6 × 0.7 × 0.2 = 0.0084. This is very small.
也就等于 0.1 × 0.6 × 0.7 × 0.2 = 0.0084 结果很小
It's less than 1%.
低于 1%
What we mean by this is that if the model is given by these probability spaces,
也就是说如果模型是呈这种概率空间
then the probability that the points are of these colors is 0.0084.
那么这些点是这些颜色的概率是 0.0084
Now let's do this for both models.
我们对这两个模型分别进行概率计算
As we saw the model on the left tells us that the probabilities of
可以看出 左侧模型所得到的
these points being of those colors is 0.0084.
这四个点分别是这些颜色的概率是 0.0084
If we do the same thing for the model on the right.
如果对右侧模型进行同样的计算
Let's say we get that the probabilities of the two points in
假设右侧两个点
the right being blue are 0.7 and
是蓝色的概率分别为 0.7 和 0.9
0.9 and of the two points in the left being red are 0.8 and 0.6.
左侧两个点是红色的概率分别为 0.8 和 0.6
When we multiply these we get 0.3024 which is around 30%.
然后将它们相乘 结果是 0.3024 约为 30%
This is much higher than 0.0084.
比 0.0084 高多了
Thus, we confirm that the model on the right is better because it makes
因此可以确定 右侧的模型更好
the arrangement of the points much more likely to have those colors.
因为这些点的分布更有可能是它们所示的这些颜色
So now, what we do is the following?
后面的计算如何进行呢？
We start from the bad modeling,
我们从较差的这个模型开始
calculate the probability that the points are those colors,
计算这些点是这些颜色的概率
multiply them and we obtain the total probability is 0.0084.
将这些概率相乘 得出总概率是 0.0084
Now if we just had a way to maximize this probability we can increase
如果我们可以通过一种方式最大化这一概率
it all the way to 0.3024.
我们可以将其一直增大到 0.3024
Thus, our new goal becomes precisely that,
因此 我们的新目标就是
to maximize this probability.
最大化这一概率
This method, as we stated before,
正如之前提到的
is called maximum likelihood.
这个方法叫做最大似然法